Guide to the Speeches and Articles by and about Presidents of Yale University
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Speeches of Howard Lamar, 1992-1993; Accession 2000-A-020
  - Howard R. Lamar Speeches, 1992-1993
    - City and State Official Reception, September22,1992 (Box 1)
    - Yale Varsity Night Dinner, September 21, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Alumni Rhode Island, September 19, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Rhode Island Luncheon, September 19, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Discovered Lands Opening, September 18, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Graduate & Professional Student Assembly, September 8, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Beinecke Portraits, September 16, 1992 (Box 1)
    - The Freshman Address, August 29, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Pre-Registration Orientation Program, August 19, 1992 (Box 1)
- Talks, speeches, statements, and publications of Benno C. Schimdt, 1985-1992; Accession 2001-A-157
  - Talks/Speeches
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1988 May 29 (Box 1)
    - American Heritage Award Dinner Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith), 1988 May 26 (Box 1)
    - Honors Dinner, 1988 May 25 (Box 1)
    - Sterling Scholars, 5-11-88 (Box 1)
    - Long Service Awards Dinner, 4-28-88 (Box 1)
    - 350th Anniversary of New Haven Concert, 4-24-88 (Box 1)
    - Physician's Building Dedication, 4-23-1988 (Box 1)
    - U.S. Senate Committee Testimony, 4-18-1988 (Box 1)
    - Introductions Law School Panel, 4-15-1988 (Box 1)
    - Reunion Dinner-Engineering & Applied Science, 4-15-1988 (Box 1)
    - Community Service Award Dinner, 4-5-1988 (Box 1)
    - Connecticut Special Olympics, 2-24-1988 (Box 1)
    - XIV Annual Yale Model United Nations, 1-29-1988 (Box 1)
    - Bicentennial of U.S. Constitution Delaware State Bar Assoc., 11-30-1987 (Box 1)
    - Ambassador's Roundtable, 11-23-1987 (Box 1)
    - Yale-Harvard Football Game Re: Tom Bergin, 11-21-1987 (Box 1)
    - Plaque Honoring William H. Taft, 12-9-1987 (Box 1)
    - Robert Bernstein Tribute, 11-16-1987 (Box 1)
    - Introduction of Elie Wiesel, 11-4-1987 (Box 1)
    - Benhaven, 10-29-1987 (Box 1)
    - AYA Alumni Dinner, 10-23-1987 (Box 1)
    - AYA 31st Assembly, 10-22-1987 (Box 1)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference, 10-16-1987 (Box 1)
    - Association of New York Bar, 10-13-1987 (Box 1)
    - Inauguration of John Lahey, Quinnipiac College, 10-11-1987 (Box 1)
    - Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund for Medical Research, 10-9-1987 (Box 1)
    - United Way Kick-Off, 9-28-1987 (Box 1)
    - Designing New Haven's Future, 9-18-1987 (Box 1)
    - Judicial Conference 3rd Circuit Bicentennial, 9-17-1987 (Box 1)
    - Hillel New Year's Reception, 9-15-1987 (Box 1)
    - Seminar-Centennial of the NIH, 9-9-1987 (Box 1)
    - G&P Assembly, 9-3-1987 (Box 1)
    - Freshman Address, 8-29-1987 (Box 1)
    - Ditchley Foundation Lecture, 8-17-1987 (Box 1)
    - Dedication of ESTU Accelerator, 8-7-1987 (Box 1)
    - New Haven Green Remarks, 6-4-1987 (Box 1)
    - Baccalaureate Speech, 5-24-1987 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meeting, 5-14-1987 (Box 1)
    - Medical School Luncheon, 5-17-1987 (Box 1)
    - Watson Hall Dedication, 5-5-1987 (Box 1)
    - Meiklejohn Lecture-Brown University, 4-28-1987 (Box 1)
    - AYA Assembly, 4-23-1987 (Box 1)
    - Yale-New Haven Teachers Institute, 4-20-1987 (Box 1)
    - Volunteer Service Reception, 4-15-1987 (Box 1)
    - Human Resource Meeting, 4-15-1987 (Box 1)
    - Testimony-Connecticut General Assembly, 4-2-1987 (Box 1)
    - D'Annuzio Symposium (Italian Dept.), 3-27-1987 (Box 1)
    - Johns Hopkins University, 2-22-1987 (Box 1)
    - 92nd Street Y, 2-19-1987 (Box 1)
    - M.A. Privatim Ceremony, 1-21-1987 (Box 1)
    - Walter Werner Memorial Service, 12-14-1986 (Box 1)
    - Yale Alumni/Maryland, 12-8-1986 (Box 1)
    - Installation of Chaplain Harry B. Adams, 11-16-1986 (Box 1)
    - AYA Assembly, 10-16-1986 (Box 1)
    - SOM 10th Anniversary, 11-15-1986 (Box 1)
    - Alumni Fund Convocation, 10-10-1986 (Box 1)
    - Child Study Center, 11-13-1986 (Box 1)
    - Strengthening Teaching thru Collaboration Teachers Institute, 11-6-1986 (Box 1)
    - Law School Remarks, 10-25-1986 (Box 1)
    - Vassar College Remarks, 10-11-1986 (Box 1)
    - United Way Kick-Off Campaign, 9-30-1986 (Box 1)
    - G&P Assembly, 9-8-1986 (Box 1)
    - 350th Anniversary - Harvard, 9-3-1986 (Box 1)
    - Freshman Address, 8-30-1986 (Box 2)
    - Inauguration Address, 9-20-1986 (Box 2)
    - First Yale Naval Aviation Unit, 3-24-1986 (Box 2)
  - Statements
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Mission Statement, April 1992 (Box 2)
    - American National Biography/ re: Edward Douglass White, 12/6/91 (Box 2)
    - Response/Jaynes Comm. Report, 11/11/91 (Box 2)
    - False Harmony, 11/1/91 (Box 2)
    - Statement re: graffiti on Student's residence door, 10-31-91 (Box 2)
    - Blurb/cover Bollinger's book, 10-23-91 (Box 2)
    - Facts about School of Medicine Statement, 10-91 (Box 2)
    - Message in Alumni Fund Annual Report, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Greetings in Yale Parent Newsletter, Fall, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Quote: Agreement with Lederle/American Cyanamid, 6-91 (Box 2)
    - Bouchet Summer Fellowships, 4-4-91 (Box 2)
    - Statement to Community on Campus Security, 3-7-91 (Box 2)
    - Statement: Death of Student, 2-17-91 (Box 2)
    - "Nation at War" Statement, 1-17-91 (Box 2)
    - Development/Alumni Fund Report, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - Statement: Secretary Louis Sullivan Disruption, 11-28-90 (Box 2)
    - Affirmative Action Statement, 11-5-90 (Box 2)
    - $10 million/Ninth Square, 10-11-90 (Box 2)
    - Gift of $20 million by Sid R. Bass, 10-5-90 (Box 2)
    - Events/Law School/Assault, 9-23-90 (Box 2)
    - Letter to Community re: Yale Review, 6-27-90 (Box 2)
    - New Director Peabody Museum (Alison Richard), 5-29-90 (Box 2)
    - Bass Family Gives $20 Million, 5-7-90 (Box 2)
    - Jaynes Committee to Monitor Affirmative Action Efforts, 4-23-90 (Box 2)
    - Yale Picture Book, 4-16-90 (Box 2)
    - Announcement DeVane Lecturer (Sid Altman), 4-10-90 (Box 2)
    - Memo of Understanding between City of New Haven and Yale University, 4-2-90 (Box 2)
    - Term Bill Statement, 3-8-90 (Box 2)
    - Recycling Statement, 2-26-90 (Box 2)
    - Speech by Dr. Abdul Alim Muhammad, 2-13-90 (Box 2)
    - Walter Littell's Resignation, 2-90 (Box 2)
    - Development Report, 88/89, 2-90 (Box 2)
    - Statement to Prown Committee, 1-30-90 (Box 2)
    - Susan Whetstone, President's Office, 1-17-90 (Box 2)
    - Statement on Rodin Report, 1-26-90 (Box 2)
    - Financial Statement, 12-89 (Box 2)
    - Dollars for Disaster Relief, 11-89 (Box 2)
    - Harassment Statement (Draft), 1989/1990 (Box 2)
    - Gay/Lesbian Police Incident, 11-29-1989 (Box 2)
    - Public Service Initiative, 10-25-1989 (Box 2)
    - Altman Nobel Prize, 10-12-1989 (Box 2)
    - Volvo International Tennis Tournament, 9-6-1989 (Box 2)
    - President Giamatti's Death, 9-1-1989 (Box 2)
    - Kagan Named Dean Yale College, 4-6-1989 (Box 2)
    - Rushdie Statement, 3-13-1989 (Box 2)
    - Osborn Memorial Lab Renovation, 3-6-1989 (Box 2)
    - Term Bill, 1989-1990, 3-6-1989 (Box 2)
    - Programmatic and Structural Change at SOM, 12-6-1988 (Box 2)
    - Michael E. Levine, Dean of SOM Announcement, 10-27-1988 (Box 2)
    - Assault Dorm Old Campus, 10-27-1988 (Box 2)
    - Defacement of Wall/Afro-American Center, 10-27-1988 (Box 2)
    - Honoring Dean Lloyd Richards, 10-20-1988 (Box 2)
    - Freedom of Expression Statement, 10-14-1988 (Box 2)
    - Yale Gift Totals, 10-13-1988 (Box 2)
    - Sessions, FBI, 10-12-1988 (Box 2)
    - U.S. News & World Report Ranking, 10-5-1988 (Box 2)
    - Spinelli Documents, 10-1-1988 (Box 2)
    - Statement re: Trustee Sen. David Boren, 9-27-1988 (Box 2)
    - Frank Turner Provost, 4-26-1988 (Box 2)
    - Campuses Against Racial Violence, 4-16-1988 (Box 2)
    - Statement before U.S. Senate Comm. On Commerce, Science & Transp., 4-14-1988 (Box 2)
    - Athletic Director Statement, 4-9-1988 (Box 2)
    - Term Bill Statement, 3-8-1988 (Box 2)
    - United Way Campaign, 2-12-1988 (Box 2)
    - Agreement with Local 34 and 35, 1-26-1988 (Box 2)
    - Affirmative Action Statement, 11-16-1987 (Box 2)
    - MB&B Building Press Release, 9-29-1987 (Box 2)
    - VP for Finance & Admin. (Mike Finnerty), 9-22-1987 (Box 2)
    - Connecticut Seed Venture, 8-26-1987 (Box 2)
    - Investment in New Haven Press Conf., 5-20-1987 (Box 2)
    - Whiffenpoofs Statement, 4-15-1987 (Box 2)
    - Sheila W. Wellington, Secretary, 86/87 (Box 2)
    - Record Gifts, 2-87 (Box 2)
    - Science Education for Yale Scientific, Winter, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Equal Opportunity Statement, 12-15-1986 (Box 2)
    - Press Conference/Announcement-BCS as (Box 2)
    - New President, 12-10-1985 (Box 2)
  - Publications
    - The University & Freedom, Educational Record, Winter, 1992 (Box 2)
    - International Education Pres. Comm. on Arts/Humanities, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
    - United Way Brochure, 10-90 (Box 2)
    - Chronicle of Higher Ed: Taxes on College Gifts, 6-27-90 (Box 2)
    - School of Forestry Brochure, 8-1989 (Box 2)
    - The Oxford Companion to the U.S. Supreme Court re: Peonage, 12-1989 (Box 2)
    - School of Medicine Campaign Brochure, 7-89 (Box 2)
    - Letter in Development Report, 8-1989,6-30-1989 (Box 2)
    - Letter for Old Campus '83, 6-21-1989 (Box 2)
    - White Court, (1910-1921), 6-13-1989 (Box 2)
    - Richmond is not the path for Higher Education, 2-23-1989 (Box 2)
    - New York Times article re. Richmond, 2-1989 (Box 2)
    - Bulletin re. Undergraduate Admissions, 8-1989 (Box 2)
    - Facts 1988-1989 School of Medicine, 8-18-1988 (Box 2)
    - Letter Bergen County Alumni, 2-1-1988 (Box 2)
    - Yale College Bulletin, 2-12-1988 (Box 2)
    - A Worthy Tradition - Book Review NYT, 1-13-1988 (Box 2)
    - Professionally Speaking, 1988 January (Box 2)
    - Parents Weekend Brochure for Whiffenpoofs and Whim'N Rhythm, 1987 October 9 (Box 2)
    - Facts about Yale Medicine, 1987 August 28 (Box 2)
    - Drama School Annual Report, 1987 August 28 (Box 2)
    - Boys Harbor Brochure, Fall 1987 (Box 2)
    - New York Times/New York Magazine re: First Amendment, July 1987 (Box 2)
    - The Rehnquist Court: A Watershed NYT, 1986 June 22 (Box 2)
    - New York Times Education Supplement, 1987 March 12 (Box 2)
    - Yale Parents Program Letter, 1987 July (Box 2)
    - Ivy League Football Publicity Magazine, 1986 August 6 (Box 2)
    - A Postscript for Charles Black, 1986 July (Box 2)
    - Message for Yale College Information Bulletin, 1986 February (Box 2)
    - Nebraska Press Association: An Expansion of Freedom & Contraction of Theory Stanford Law Review, 1989/1990 (Box 2)
    - Curtiss-Wright Comes Home: Executive Power and National Sec., Summer, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Principle and Prejudice: Sup. Court and Race in Progressive Era, 1991 October (Box 2)